

□ (+90 543 867 2627) | ■ egeakat@gmail.com | ♠ egeakat.com | □ egeakat | ₩ egeakat | □ egeakat

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Skills

Programming Languages Javascript, Java, Python, Go, C/C++, PHP

Back-end AWS SDK, Spring Boot, Node.js, Express, Flask, Laravel, REST API, MVC

Front-end React.js, Vue.js, Tailwind

DevOps Jenkins, GNU/Linux, Serverless, AWS CLI, Bash, SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL,

Languages English, Turkish

Work Experience

Arçelik Global Ankara, Turkey

IOT R&D TRAINEE ENGINEER

Mar. 2022 - Apr. 2024

· Took part in the Cloud Development Team, crafting innovative solutions for the Internal tools squad using JavaScript, Java, and AWS Cloud services for both backend and frontend applications.

 Architected and deployed scalable solutions using various AWS services including Lambda, S3, ApiGateway, and CloudFormation etc. enhancing system efficiency and reliability.

Hacettepe University Ankara, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND CONTENT SPECIALIST

Nov. 2018 - Mar. 2022

- · Led the development of web management systems, enhancing the digital presence of the Lifelong Learning Center through innovative content and social media strategies.
- Utilized PHP, Vue.js, GIMP, WordPress, and Google Analytics to develop, manage, and analyze online content, significantly increasing user engagement.

Onedio Ankara, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Aug. 2020 - Sep. 2020

- · Contributed to the creation of Onedio Vitrin, a platform for sharing paid or sponsored articles, enhancing the company's content delivery
- Designed database structures and developed ORM models, facilitating robust data management and streamlined CRUD operations.
- Employed Node.js, leveraging KOA and Sequelize for backend development, improving application functionality and performance.

Picus Security Inc. Ankara, Turkey

BACKEND DEVELOPER

- Sep. 2019 Nov. 2019 · Integrated AWS and Zoho CRM into a dev-ops automation tool, streamlining operations and enhancing customer relationship management.
- · Specialized in Python Flask development, contributing to the backend architecture and system integration efforts.

Education

Hacettepe University

Ankara, Turkey

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2018 - Feb. 2024

- · Studied Computer Science and Engineering
- · Took various courses mostly focusing on Data Engineering, Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence
- 2.86 GPA

Extracurricular Activity _____

Hacettepe Free Software Society

Ankara, Turkey

FOUNDER & CHAIRMAN

Nov. 2019 - Oct. 2021

- Assembled and led the board of directors of Hacettepe Free Software Society
- Have been the organizer for many software courses and the lecturer for some of them
- · Organized many panels and interviews with some of the important people from the Academy and the leading industry experts
- Raised awareness about free software
- · Created a friendly environment for Hacettepe University students to socialize, self improve and network
- Developed the website and the systems needed for the organization

EGE AKAT · RÉSUMÉ

ACM Hacettepe Ankara, Turkey

Sep. 2018 - Sep. 2019

R & D TEAM MEMBER

• Took part in the ACM Hacettepe R&D Team as a web developer and developed many projects

Summary

As a cloud engineer and a computer science and engineering graduate, I have a strong passion for creating engineering solutions that are based on modern structures. Even though I define myself as a learner I am currently trying to become a Cloud engineering expert with a passion for the cloud. During my studies in university, I mostly focused on various machine learning, data processing and artificial intelligence courses. I am also interested in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning and one of my goals is to develop my own models and deploy them.

I define myself as a really quick learner and a swiss knife engineer. I have no problems adapting to different fields of work and can accustom myself to any projects in almost real time.

In my personal life I'm an amateur chess player. I also enjoy doing research in my free time whether it's about science, psychology, history or any interesting topic I might be curious about. I also have an interest in Neurochemistry and psychology. I enjoy researching and learning about how human consciousness and behaviour works and how can we understand it and make it better, healthier.

EGE AKAT · RÉSUMÉ